<u>linkedin.com/in/johanbester</u> • Portfolio at <u>johanbester66.wordpress.com</u> • <u>github.com/johanbester</u>

# Front-end web developer and IT generalist with several years of web building, web maintenance and site management experience.

I'm a technically proficient business professional and IT generalist with solid experience of the website development and deployment lifecycle, able to effectively handle multiple development activities concurrently, while delivering reliable, maintainable, quality code solutions - on time and on budget.

**Technical Skills** 

- o Experienced building fully scalable, responsive websites to fit different devices and screen sizes.
- o Develop code using HTML, CSS, Zurb Foundations, Bootstrap, and vanilla JavaScript.
- o Experienced coding sites to meet W3C and WCAG 2.0 ADA accessible compliance standards.
- o Umbraco Certified Professional with 3 years of experience building UMBRACO websites.
- o Advanced user of Windows OS proficient in Microsoft Office suite.
- Comfortable in the use of wide ranging and diverse applications and products -- IDE tools; online tools and coding apps.; web browsers; email clients; productivity apps; helpdesk apps; Google services; accounting packages; and various CDN, SCM, FTP, CMS, PIM and other tools.
- o Strong working knowledge of social media and internet marketing applications.

#### **Continued Learning**

- Savvy Coders full-stack Web Development Boot Camp June 2020 cohort: Enrolled in an intense
   12-week program aimed at guiding students into becoming fully qualified web developers.
- Capstone project: In process of developing a SPA solution called "STIX FMA Fun Finder" to help FMA
  practitioners search within a zip code radius for clubs and FMA events, throughout the USA. Build the SPA
  to run with Parcel in Node, and coded the HTML5, CSS3 and vanilla JavaScript in the VS Code IDE.

#### **Employment History**

The Accel Group (TAG), St. Louis, Missouri

**(01**/2015 - Present)

## General web support, web development and web maintenance contractor (Part time)

- o Working remotely, I provide web support, development, and maintenance services for the clients of TAG.
- o Managed websites for about 20 Community Credit Unions that collectively served approximately 75,000 customers in Missouri, Illinois, and Kansas. Also managed email services for several of these clients.
- o Built the TAG company website, and 5 client websites using ASP.Net with VB code-behind.
- Provided access for disadvantaged users to several websites by upgrading the sites to attain to ADA WCAG
   2.0 accessible compliance standards.
- o Managed and maintained the daily operations of 15 legacy banking websites built in classic ASP.
- Regularly perform website maintenance to update text copy, graphics and code often on a weekly basis.
- o Redeployed websites to different web hosts, managed domain names, installed SSL certificates, etc.
- o Routinely called on to do problem solving to fix web services or email issues / outages.
- Escalate issues with 3<sup>rd</sup> party service providers like Microsoft Azure, CloudFlare, GoDaddy, etc., and managed problem resolution.

**Key technologies**: MS Visual Studio, HTML, CSS, ASP.Net, VB.Net, vanilla JavaScript, Zurb Foundations CSS framework, Atlassian Bitbucket, FileZilla, MS Azure, MXToolbox, CloudFlare CDN, Zoho Suite and Email, Zoho Invoicing, FreshDesk support desk.

Bundy & Associates, Inc. St. Louis, Missouri

(09/2014 - 12/2019)

#### General computer support, web development, and social media contractor (Part time)

- Worked remotely providing general IT support, web development and maintenance, social media management, and other business and IT functions as directed, for clients like ACI Distributors, TAG, Forklifts of St. Louis, Horst, etc.
- o Helped build the Bundy company website, the AcumenB2B supply chain solution, the AcumenB2B website, and the Wildlife Farming website among other.
- o Co-develop three websites for Forklifts of St. Louise (forkliftsofstlouis.com) using the Umbraco.
- Wrote the ACI Dealers-website user's manual, edited video training sessions, and helped translate significant parts of the Horst website into French.

**Key technologies:** MS Visual Studio, HTML, CSS, ASP.Net, VB.NET, JavaScript, Zurb Foundations, Bootstrap, Umbraco CMS, Atlassian Bitbucket & SourceTree, FileZilla, MS Azure, MXToolbox, CloudFlare CDN, MS SQL Server Management Studio, Social Media and Internet Marketing applications, etc.

Associate Sales & Marketing ASM, (for Sam's Club Glen Carbon, IL)

(2013 - 09/2014)

#### Event promotion specialist (Part-time)

o Interacted face-to-face with customers in a fast-paced environment promoting various products items; Consistently over-preforming above 100% on targets, regularly selling out on promotional product lines.

RTI International, based in Durham, NC

(2012 - 2013)

### Remote online and telephone customer services IT support contractor

 Received rave reviews for daily assisting a worldwide customer base remotely online and via telephone with basic first-line IT support, trouble shooting, and incident report logging for a wide range of general and proprietary applications and systems.

Pride Cleaning and Restoration Inc., St. Louis, MO

(12/2006 - 10/2010)

## Business office manager and bookkeeper

- Managed business operations and corporate affairs for an absent owner. Managed safety and compliance, insurance, personnel administration, marketing, Social Media and corporate branding.
- Successfully automated business administration, curtailed debt, turned an ailing company around and steered it through the 2008-2009 recession.

**Education** 

Lewis and Clark Community College, Godfrey, IL USA

(2011 - 2014)

# Associate in Sciences, Computer Management Information Systems (AS CMIS)

College Foundation and Board of Trustees scholarship recipient; Member of Phi Theta Kappa International honor society; Consistently honored on the Presidents list of highest achievers (2011-2014); President of the Student Sustainability Association, and Webmaster for the student newspaper.

Certifications

0	Agile Certified Practitioner (ACP) certification	2020
0	Umbraco Certified Professional developer	2020
0	Responsive Web Design developer certification	2019
0	Internet Marketing certification	2011